Hello and welcome to Real easyy English We're back with another conversation in easyy English to help you learn I'm Neil and I'm Becker and you can find a video
Version of this podcast on our website that comes with subtitles to help your learning that's@bbclearningenglish.com. .
Hi Becca, how are you I'm really well Thank you Neil how about yourself I'm very well you look very relaxed though so what have you been doing Well
I recently been to the beach I went to my to visit my parents and they live quite close to the beach so that's probably why
I look and feel very relaxed the beach fantastic Well we are talking about the beach today Okay becca when you,
Have a beach day, do you like to sunbathe, which means lying on the beach in the sun, doing nothing?
Or do you prefer to do something active like swimming.
People often play sports on the beach that kind of thing I do love to sunbathe, but we don't have.
A lot of sun in the UK and the temperatures aren't always the best for sunbathing, but it's still something I really enjoy doing I'll sun baththe for a little bit I'll kind of,
I'll cook under the sun and then I'll go for a swim to cool down that yeah, I prefer more relaxing activities, I know some people enjoy like beachvolleyball.
Or some people like long, long coastal walks.
But yeah, I prefer kind of just staying in one one spot and relaxing there.
How about you.
I prefer to do something active at the beach swimming.
I like to play beach football, beach cricket, whatever, and if I am.
Lying or some bathing I like to read a book, but yeah, it's a bit uncomfortable.
It can be, it can be uncomfortable.
Yeah, Also you mentioned that you like playing some sports on the beach.
I imagine it can be quite difficult to play sports on a pebbly beach pebbles are small stones and very different to sandy beaches
Sand is quite soft and I guess easier for.
Beach football and beach cricket Yeah, lots of the beaches in the UK are pebble beaches with stones on them rather than sand and yes,
It can be more difficult it can really, Hurt your feet sometimes it is quite funny on a Pebbly beach to see people coming out of the sea
From their swim and then kind of, you know, finding it quite difficult to walk along the beach.
It sometimes is quite funny How about food so do you take a picnic to the beach Yeah, sometimes another reason actually we talked about Pebbly beaches.
But I really love a pebble beach because it's easier to have a picnic on a Pebble beach,
I don't know about your own experiences, but every time I sit on a sandy beach, With a lovely picnic, it always gets ruined by all of the sand exactly, you end up with a kind of.
Cruny sandwich, yeah, Sandy sandwiches, Sandy sandwiches not tasty, so I do love a picnic on the beach, but yeah you do have to be.
Careful about where you are and the wind as well Yes, especially in the UK yeah they're quite windy very windy in the UK but the world
Is full of beautiful beaches have you got a memory of a favourite beach you've been to somewhere Yes I have beautiful memories
Probably the most recent and the most beautiful was when I was in Thailand last February.
Ve cold and rainy in the UK so I decided to go to Thailand and I just remember seeing the sunset at the beach
And I'd never seen the sun so red before it was incredible so when the sun is setting and it's kind of it looks like it's going below sea level
At nighttime just beautiful stunning.
Time now to recap the vocabulary we've heard in this podcast starting with sunbathe If you sunbthe,
You sit or lie in the sunshine to relax, but you have to be careful in case you get burnt Yes,
And if you sunb for too long you might need to cool down to cool down means to do something to cool yourself when you're feeling too hot and you can do that by
Going for a swim to go for a swim.
Is to literally go swimming that it could also mean just to relax in the water We talked about two different kinds of beaches pebble beaches
And sandy beaches pebble beaches are covered in small smooth stones they can be difficult to walk on a sandy beach
Is covered in sand and sand is that fine grain.
And it's much more comfortable to walk on And lastly, we mentioned picnics, a picnic is a meal that you enjoy outside.
That's it for this episode of Real easyy English, but don't forget to go to our website to download a free worksheet that's atbblearningenglish.com. .
And we'll be back next week with another episode of real easy English bye for now goodbyee.